tenses = [
  "present simple",
  "present continuous",
  "past simple",
  "past continuous",
  "present perfect",
  "present perfect continuous",
  "past perfect",
  "past perfect continous",
  "future",
  "future continuous",
  "future perfect simple",
  "future perfect continuous",
  "conditional simple",
  "conditional continuous",
  "conditional perfect",
  "conditional perfect continous",
];

questions = [
  {
    question: "They were late because ____ train was delayed.",
    choices: ["their", "they're", "there", "thems"],
    answer: "their",
    explanation: "Their = possessive; they're = they are",
  },
  {
    question: "I don't work ____ anymore.",
    choices: ["their", "they're", "there", "thems"],
    answer: "there",
    explanation: "Their = possessive; they're = they are",
  },
  {
    question: "Don't worry about the dogs, _____ not going to bother you.",
    choices: ["their", "they're", "there", "thems"],
    answer: "they're",
    explanation: "Their = possessive; they're = they are",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In what tense is the following sentence: I will be there on Monday.",
    choices: ["future", "present", "past", "past perfect", "future perfect"],
    answer: "future",
  },
  {
    question: "In what tense is the following sentence: I have been waiting.",
    choices: [
      "present perfect",
      "future",
      "present",
      "past",
      "past perfect",
      "future perfect",
    ],
    answer: "present perfect",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentence? Nor did the evidence submitted resolve the real question__ whether Jackson is in fact Cosby's daughter.",
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
    ],
    answer: "future",
    explanation:
      "The first of a colon's five uses is to link two separate clauses by indicating a step forward from the first to the second: the step may be from an introduction to a main theme, from a cause to an effect, from a general statement to a particular instance, or from a premise to a conclusion.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentence? The days I am available are as follows__ Monday, Wednesday, and Saturday.",
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
    ],
    answer: "colon",
    explanation:
      "The second of the colon's five uses is to introduce a list of items, often after expressions such as 'the following' and 'as follows'.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentence? By 1776 it seemed clear to numerous inhabitants of the westen areas of the Connecticut River valley that the fight against tyranny had assumed a two-fold character__ 'We are contending agains tthe same enemy within, that is also without'.",
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
    ],
    answer: "colon",
    explanation:
      "The third of the colon's five uses is to formally introduce a wholly self-contained quotation, whether short or long.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following formal salutation? Dear Ms. Johnson__",
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
    ],
    answer: "colon",
    explanation:
      "The fourth of the colon's five uses is after the salutation in formal correspondence.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following book's title and subtitle? Will Rogers__ A Biography",
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
    ],
    answer: "colon",
    explanation:
      "The fifth of a comma's five uses is to separate elements such as a book's title and subtitle.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentence? I am going to dinner with the Joneses__ the Smiths__ and the Nelsons.",
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
    ],
    answer: "comma",
    explanation:
      "The first of the comma's nine uses is to separate items in a list of more than two.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentence? I would love to see her and the baby__ and I will be here all day.",
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
      "none",
    ],
    answer: "comma",
    explanation:
      "The second of the comma's nine uses is to separate coordinated main clauses.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentences? 1) Moreover__ he didn't even want to go fishing in the first place. 2) In the meantime__ don't worry about it. 3) If everything goes as planned__ I'll be retired by the time I'm 55.",
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
      "none",
    ],
    answer: "comma",
    explanation:
      "The third of the comma's nine uses is to separate most introductory matter from the main clause, often to prevent misunderstanding. The introductory matter may be a word, a phrase, or a subordinate clause. Matter that is very short may not need this comma (as in 'On Friday we leave for Florida').",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentences? 1) I am sure__ however__ that it will not happen. 2) Fred__ who is bald__ complained of the cold.",
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
      "none",
    ],
    answer: "comma",
    explanation:
      "The fourth of the comma's nine uses is to mark the beginning and end of a parenthetical word or phrase, an appositive, or a nonrestrictive clause.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentence? A cautious__ reserved man.",
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
      "none",
    ],
    answer: "comma",
    explanation:
      "The fifth of the comma's nine uses is to separate adjectives that each qualify a noun in the same way.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentences? 1) He is a distinguished__ foreign journalist. 2) She wore a bright__ red tie.",
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
      "none",
    ],
    answer: "none",
    explanation:
      "When adjectives qualify nouns in different ways, or when one adjective qualifies a noun phrase containing another adjective, no comma is used.",
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentence? "Honey, I\'m home__" Sarah said.',
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
      "none",
    ],
    answer: "comma",
    explanation:
      "The sixth of the comma's nine uses is to separate a direct quotation from its attribution.",
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentence? TV loves catchphrases such as ___ "Honey, I\'m home".',
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
      "none",
      "hyphen",
    ],
    answer: "none",
    explanation:
      "No punctuation is necessary when the quoted speech is woven into the syntax of the sentence.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentences? 1) Having had breakfast__ I went for a walk. 2) The sermon over__ the congregation filed out. 3) Fellow priests__ the clergy must unite in reforming the system of electing bishops.",
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
      "none",
      "hyphen",
    ],
    answer: "comma",
    explanation:
      "The seventh of the comma's nine uses is to separate a participial phrase, a verbless phrase, or a vocative.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use after the following salutation (1) and complimentary close (2) in an informal letter? 1) Dear Rebecca__ 2) Yours sincerely__",
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
      "none",
      "hyphen",
    ],
    answer: "comma",
    explanation:
      "The eight of the comma's nine uses is to mark the end of the salutation and the complimentary close in informal letters.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following address (1) and date (2)? 1) #8 Country Club Dr.__ Amherst__ Massachussetts 2) March 2__ 1998.",
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
      "none",
      "hyphen",
    ],
    answer: "comma",
    explanation:
      "The ninth of the comma's nine uses is to separate parts of an address or a date.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentences? Only if this were true__ could it be said that John F. Kennedy was a great president.",
    choices: [
      "none",
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
      "hyphen",
    ],
    answer: "none",
    explanation: "No punctuation necessary.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentence? Unfortunately, moral beauty in art__ like physical beauty in a person__ is extremely perishable.",
    choices: [
      "em-dash",
      "colon",
      "period",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "en-dash",
      "none",
      "hyphen",
    ],
    answer: "em-dash",
    explanation:
      "The em-dash is used to enclose a parenthetical remark and can often clarify a sentence that is clogged up with commas.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentence? I heard this anecdote from Mikhail Gorbachev__ who had heard it from Gromyko himself__ when I paid him a visit, earlier this year, to talk about the vodka anniversary.",
    choices: [
      "em-dash",
      "colon",
      "period",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "en-dash",
      "none",
      "hyphen",
    ],
    answer: "em-dash",
    explanation:
      "The em-dash be used to enclose a parenthetical remark and can often clarify a sentence that is clogged up with commas.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentence? On July 22, the company was awarded the largest privatization contract ever for a prison__ a 2048-bed minimum security facility in Taft, California.",
    choices: [
      "em-dash",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "en-dash",
      "none",
      "hyphen",
    ],
    answer: "em-dash",
    explanation: "The em-dash can be used to replace the colon.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following phrases? 1) the 1914__1918 war 2) the nature__nurture debate 3) the Dallas__Toronto__Quebec route 4) The Fischer__Spassky match 5) the Marxist__Trotskyite split",
    choices: [
      "en-dash",
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "none",
      "hyphen",
    ],
    answer: "en-dash",
    explanation:
      "The en-dash, which is half as wide as the em-dash, is distinct (in print) from the hyphen. It joins pairs or groups of words to show a range, and also indicates movement or tension (rather than cooperation or unity). It is often equivalent to 'to' or 'versus'.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following phrases? 1) credit__card application 2) high__frequency sounds 3) natural__gas pipeline",
    choices: [
      "hyphen",
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
      "none",
    ],
    answer: "hyphen",
    explanation:
      "Hyphens are used in the realm of phrasal adjectives. If two or more consecutive words make sense only when understood together as an adjective modifying a noun that follows, those words (excluding the noun) should be hyphenated.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentence? The cat walked down the sidewalk__ A woman approached it and attempted to pet it.",
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
      "none",
    ],
    answer: "period",
    explanation:
      "The period is used for two purposes. First, it ends all sentences that are not questions or exclamations. The next word normally begins with a capital letter. Second, it has traditionally indicated abbreviations, but this use is on the decline.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentence? But Shakespeare's language appears entirely familiar to us, although it is almost 400 years old__ the spelling, the vocabulary, the shapes of the words and phrases seem to have changed but little in that time.",
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "comma",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
      "none",
      "hyphen",
    ],
    answer: "semicolon",
    explanation:
      "The semicolon (;) is a kind of supercomma. It separates sentence parts that need a more distinct break than a comma can signal, but are too closely connected to be made into separate sentences. Four uses are common. First, it can be used to unite closely connected sentences; typically, as in this very sentence, there is no conjunction between clauses.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentence? But Elizabeth was not formed for ill-humour__ and though every prospect of her own was destroyed for the evening, it could not dwell long on her spirits; and having told all her griefs to Charlotte Lucas, whom she had not seen for a week, she was soon able to make a voluntary transition to the oddities of her cousin, and to point him out to her in particular notice.",
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
      "none",
      "hyphen",
    ],
    answer: "semicolon",
    explanation:
      "The semicolon (;) is a kind of supercomma. It separates sentence parts that need a more distinct break than a comma can signal, but are too closely connected to be made into separate sentences. Four uses are common. The second is to separate coordinate clauses in long, complex sentences. This use was more common in the 19th century than it is today.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentence? Between 1815 and 1850, Americans constructed elaborate networks of roads, canals, and early railroad lines__ opened up wide areas of newly acquired land for settlement and trade__ and began to industrialize manufacturing.",
    choices: [
      "colon",
      "period",
      "apostrophe",
      "semicolon",
      "em-dash",
      "en-dash",
      "none",
      "hyphen",
    ],
    answer: "semicolon",
    explanation:
      "The semicolon (;) is a kind of supercomma. It separates sentence parts that need a more distinct break than a comma can signal, but are too closely connected to be made into separate sentences. Four uses are common. The third is to separate items in a series when any element in a series contains an internal comma.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is the best punctuation mark to use in the following sentence? There is never anything sexy about Lautrec's art__ but there also is never anything deliberately, sarcastically anti-feminist in it.",
    choices: ["colon", "apostrophe", "semicolon", "en-dash", "none", "hyphen"],
    answer: "semicolon",
    explanation:
      "The semicolon (;) is a kind of supercomma. It separates sentence parts that need a more distinct break than a comma can signal, but are too closely connected to be made into separate sentences. Four uses are common. The fourth use is to simply give a weightier pause than a comma would. This use is discretionary. A comma would do, but the writer wants a stronger stop.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Fill in the blank with the correct word: Engine builders will ____ executive privilege, making sure the session is nothing more than a light workout.",
    choices: ["exert", "assert"],
    answer: "assert",
    explanation:
      "Writers sometimes confuse these words. Assert = (1) to state with force and confidence; (2) to exercise or demonstrate (authority, a right, a privilege, etc.); or (3) to behave or speak forcefully. Exert = (1) to put forth or apply (energy, force, strength, etc.) to something; or (2) to make a physical or mental effort.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Fill in the blank with the correct word: The team members ____ all their strength and won the tug-of-war.",
    choices: ["exerted", "asserted", "inserted", "flirted"],
    answer: "exert",
    explanation:
      "Writers sometimes confuse these words. Assert = (1) to state with force and confidence; (2) to exercise or demonstrate (authority, a right, a privilege, etc.); or (3) to behave or speak forcefully. Exert = (1) to put forth or apply (energy, force, strength, etc.) to something; or (2) to make a physical or mental effort.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Fill in the blank with the correct word: Do you know where ____ going?",
    choices: ["you're", "your", "yore"],
    answer: "you're",
    explanation:
      "'Your' indicates a possession. \"You're\" is short for 'you are'.",
  },
  {
    question: "Fill in the blank with the correct word: Can I have ___ coat?",
    choices: ["you're", "your", "yore"],
    answer: "your",
    explanation:
      "'Your' indicates a possession. \"You're\" is short for 'you are'.",
  },
  {
    question: "Name the tense of the following sentence: I work.",
    choices: tenses,
    answer: "present simple",
    explanation: "Answer: present simple.",
  },
  {
    question: "Name the tense of the following sentence: I'm working.",
    choices: tenses,
    answer: "present continuous",
    explanation:
      "Answer: present continuous. Something is happening at the same time of speaking or around it. Future meaning: when you have already decided and arranged to do it (a fixed plan, date).",
  },
  {
    question: "Name the tense of the following sentence: I worked.",
    choices: tenses,
    answer: "past simple",
    explanation: "Answer: past simple. An action finished in the past.",
  },
  {
    question: "Name the tense of the following sentence: I was working.",
    choices: tenses,
    answer: "past continuous",
    explanation:
      "Answer: past continuous. Use this when (1) an action happened in the middle of another action, or (2) when someone was doing something at a certain time in the past (you do not know whether it is finished or not).",
  },
  {
    question: "Name the tense of the following sentence: I have worked.",
    choices: tenses,
    answer: "present perfect",
    explanation:
      "Answer: present perfect. Use this (1) when you say that something has happened or is finished in the past and it has a connection to the present, or (2) when an action started in the past and continues up to the present.",
  },
  {
    question: "Name the tense of the following sentence: I have been working.",
    choices: tenses,
    answer: "present perfect continuous",
    explanation:
      "Answer: present perfect continuous. Action began in the past and has just stopped.",
  },
  {
    question: "Name the tense of the following sentence: I had worked.",
    choices: tenses,
    answer: "past perfect",
    explanation:
      "Answer: past perfect. Mostly used when two actions in a story are related to each other: the action that had already happened is put into past perfect, the other action into simple past.",
  },
  {
    question: "Name the tense of the following sentence: I had been working.",
    choices: tenses,
    answer: "past perfect continuous",
    explanation: "Answer: past perfect continuous.",
  },
  {
    question: "Name the tense of the following sentence: He will work.",
    choices: tenses,
    answer: "future",
    explanation: "Answer: future",
  },
  {
    question: "Name the tense of the following sentence: I'll be working.",
    choices: tenses,
    answer: "future continuous",
    explanation:
      "Answer: future continuous. An action will be in progress at a certain time in the future.",
  },
  {
    question: "Name the tense of the following sentence: I'll have worked.",
    choices: tenses,
    answer: "future perfect simple",
    explanation:
      "Answer: future perfect simple. Something will have happened before a certain time in the future.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Name the tense of the following sentence: He'll have been working.",
    choices: tenses,
    answer: "future perfect continuous",
    explanation:
      "Answer: future perfect continuous. Something will already have happened before a certain time in the future.",
  },
  {
    question: "Name the tense of the following sentence: He would work.",
    choices: tenses,
    answer: "conditional simple",
    explanation: "Answer: conditional simple",
  },
  {
    question: "Name the tense of the following sentence: I would be working.",
    choices: tenses,
    answer: "conditional continuous",
    explanation: "Answer: conditional continuous",
  },
  {
    question: "Name the tense of the following sentence: I would have worked.",
    choices: tenses,
    answer: "conditional perfect",
    explanation:
      "Answer: conditional perfect. Something that might have happened in the past, but it's too late now.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Name the tense of the following sentence: I would have been working.",
    choices: tenses,
    answer: "conditional perfect continuous",
    explanation: "Answer: conditional perfect continuous",
  },
  {
    question: "We need to get our ___ numbers up.",
    choices: ["sales", "sale's"],
    answer: "sales",
    explanation:
      "Don't use an apostrophe if the 's' is there simply to make a word plural.",
  },
  {
    question: "He starts work ____ at 8 a.m.",
    choices: ["every day", "everyday"],
    answer: "every day",
    explanation:
      "'Everyday' is an adjective describing something that's very common, like an everyday occurence. 'Every day' is an adverbial phrase that means each day.",
  },
  {
    question: "Sunrise is an ____ occurrence.",
    choices: ["every day", "everyday"],
    answer: "everyday",
    explanation:
      "'Everyday' is an adjective describing something that's very common, like an everyday occurence. 'Every day' is an adverbial phrase that means each day.",
  },
  {
    question: "The marketing manager told Riley and __ to talk with her.",
    choices: ["me", "I", "myself"],
    answer: "me",
    explanation:
      "Use 'I' when it’s the subject of a verb (e.g., 'I walked to the store'). Use 'me' when the pronoun is the object of the verb, or when the verb is doing something to someone or something (e.g., 'the dog followed me to the store').",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The company just celebrated ___ eighth year since it went public.",
    choices: ["its", "it's", "it is"],
    answer: "its",
    explanation:
      "Usually, an apostrophe indicates possession, but not in this case. Only use 'it's' as a contraction of 'it is'.",
  },
  {
    question: "____ than 50 people showed up for the presentation.",
    choices: ["fewer", "less"],
    answer: "fewer",
    explanation:
      "Use 'fewer' for numbered, countable things. Use 'less' for things that can't be counted, or with numbers when they are a single or total unit that measures distance, amount, or time.",
  },
  {
    question: "I want to drink ____ wine than last time.",
    choices: ["less", "fewer"],
    answer: "less",
    explanation:
      "Use 'fewer' for numbered, countable things. Use 'less' for things that can't be counted, or with numbers when they are a single or total unit that measures distance, amount, or time.",
  },
  {
    question: "I could just _____ down and go to sleep.",
    choices: ["lie", "lay", "lain", "laid"],
    answer: "lie",
    explanation:
      "To lie is intransitive, which means it doesn’t have an object and doesn’t do anything to anyone or anything else (e.g., I lie down).  To lay is transitive, which means it does have an object, as in something or someone the verb is doing something to (e.g., I lay down my head).",
  },
  {
    question: "Yesterday, I ____ on the couch and took a nap.",
    choices: ["lay", "lied", "laid", "lain"],
    answer: "lay",
    explanation: "'Lay' is the past tense of the intransitive verb 'lie'.",
  },
  {
    question: "I ___ the book on the table.",
    choices: ["lay", "lie"],
    answer: "lay",
    explanation:
      "'Lay' is correct in the present tense in this case because it is transitive (takes an object). If it were intransitive, 'lie' would be correct (as in 'I lie on the table')",
  },
  {
    question: "The people ___ reach their sales target will get a reward.",
    choices: ["this", "who", "which", "whom"],
    answer: "who",
    explanation:
      "Use 'who' when talking about people; use 'that' when talking about things.",
  },
  {
    question: "She played the guitar ___ has seven strings.",
    choices: ["which", "that"],
    answer: "that",
    explanation:
      "Use 'that' to introduce a restrictive clause; use 'which' to introduce a non-restrictive clause. The latter is usually introduced by a comma.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The decision is the second defeat in five months for the French government, ____ has been attempting to delay liberalising its domestic air transport market while it seeks to restructure its loss-making flag carrier.",
    choices: ["which", "that"],
    answer: "which",
    explanation:
      "Use 'that' to introduce a restrictive clause; use 'which' to introduce a non-restrictive clause. The latter is usually introduced by a comma.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "By _____ changes the limited partners can reap specified rewards.",
    choices: ["affecting", "effecting"],
    answer: "effecting",
    explanation:
      "In ordinary usage, affect is always a verb; it means 'to influence; to have an effect on.' Effect is primarily a noun meaning 'result' or 'consequence. Using affect (= to influence) for effect (= to bring about) is an old error.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "She doubted the majority flip would have a huge ____ on the council.",
    choices: ["affect", "effect"],
    answer: "effect",
    explanation:
      "In ordinary usage, affect is always a verb; it means 'to influence; to have an effect on.' Effect, is primarily a noun meaning 'result' or 'consequence.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "It has ____ me when I have seen billboards that contained misspelled words, punctuation errors, and other things that are fundamental to the English language.",
    choices: ["irritated", "aggravated"],
    answer: "irritated",
    explanation:
      "Strictly speaking, 'aggravate' means 'to make worse; exacerbate' and shouldn't be used to mean 'irritate' or 'annoy'.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Davis ____ residents that they can help decide which trees are to be cut.",
    choices: ["assured", "ensured", "insured"],
    answer: "assured",
    explanation:
      "A person 'assures' (makes promises to, convinces) other people; a person 'ensures' (makes certain) that things occur or that events take place. 'Assure' takes a personal object.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The suspension of talks until midmorning ____ another gridlocked rush-hour throughout the San Franscisco Bay area.",
    choices: ["ensured", "assured", "insured"],
    answer: "ensured",
    explanation:
      "A person 'assures' (makes promises to, convinces) other people; a person 'ensures' (makes certain) that things occur or that events take place. 'Assure' takes a personal object. 'Insure' should be restricted to financial contexts involving indemnification.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "And the police are removing the homeless--by police rides to the edge of town, by ____ issuing of citations for camping, by mass towing of vehicles, and by routine discarding of people's belongings.",
    choices: ["continual", "continuous"],
    answer: "continual",
    explanation:
      "Continual = frequently recurring; intermittent. Continuous = occurring without interruption; unceasing.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Crow Canyon archaeologists want to study the 12th and 13th-century village to determine exactly when it was inhabited and whether it was occupied _____ or intermittently.",
    choices: ["continuously", "continually"],
    answer: "continuously",
    explanation:
      "Continual = frequently recurring; intermittent. Continuous = occurring without interruption; unceasing.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "He may empathize with modern American theater, but his ____ in American opera is resounding.",
    choices: ["disinterest", "uninterest"],
    answer: "uninterest",
    explanation:
      "Disinterest = impartiality or freedom from bias or from chance of financial benefit. Uninterest = lack of concern or attention.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "After popping in to say hello to Sue's dad, we walked ___ up Main Street to the Maritime Museum.",
    choices: ["farther", "further"],
    answer: "farther",
    explanation:
      "'Farther' refers to physical distances; 'further' refers to figurative distances.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Chad Johnson has taken the florid displays of flanker ego even ____, brashly predicting victories...",
    choices: ["farther", "further"],
    answer: "further",
    explanation:
      "'Farther' refers to physical distances; 'further' refers to figurative distances.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A record rider turnout, fueled by the mayor's earlier pledge to end the escort and crack down on cyclists ______ traffic laws, poured into the streets on an improvised route.",
    choices: ["flaunting", "flouting"],
    answer: "flouting",
    explanation:
      "'Flout' = to contravene or disregard; to treat with contempt. 'Flaunt' = to show off or parade something in an ostentatious manner.",
  },
];

module.exports = questions;
